disruptorbeam.com 2017-06-09

# Privacy Policy — Disruptor Beam

### This Privacy Policy written in English

• Klicken Sie hier, um die deutsche Fassung anzeigen zu lassen: Datenschutzrichtlinie von Disruptor Beam (deutsche Fassung)  
• Haga clic aquí para verla en español: Política de privacidad de Disruptor Beam (español)  
• Cette Politique de confidentialité est écrite en anglais. Cliquer ici pour la lire en français : Politique de confidentialité Disruptor Beam (français)  
• Clique aqui para visualizá-la em português: Política de Privacidade da Disruptor Beam (português)

## Last updated September 30, 2016

Disruptor Beam, Inc., (“Disruptor Beam,” “Us” or “We”) may provide games, applications, products and services (individually, a “Service”, and collectively, the "Services") via websites owned by Disruptor Beam (without limitation, http://DisruptorBeam.com) or through third-party services or networks (including, without limitation, Facebook and Kongregate), or distributed through third-party application stores such as the Apple App Store or Google Play, or other web sites and applications owned, operated, licensed or controlled by Disruptor Beam (the "Disruptor Beam Sites" or the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy applies to your use of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, unless a particular Service contains or links to a separate Privacy Policy.

Disruptor Beam respects the privacy of its online visitors and users of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services. Disruptor Beam recognizes the importance of protecting certain information collected from users and has adopted this Privacy Policy that guides how Disruptor Beam collects, stores, and uses information provided from users through the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services as described below. This policy is current as of its last revision date indicated above.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. We will provide you with advance notice of the changes, for example by posting changes on our website at www.disruptorbeam.com/privacy. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website at least thirty days prior to the change becoming effective. Please also review our Privacy Policy webpage periodically to ensure you are aware of any changes. You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the date at the top of this page.

 **EU-U.S. Privacy Shield**

Disruptor Beam **** and its subsidiary company Disruptor Beam UK Ltd participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  Disruptor Beam is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. [https://www.privacyshield.gov/list]

Disruptor Beam **** is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf.  Disruptor Beam complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received **** or **** transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Disruptor Beam **** is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission.  In certain situations, Disruptor Beam **** may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

Collection, Use and Disclosure of Information

When you use any Service through a third party Social networking service such as Facebook, Kongregate, Apple GameCenter or Google Play (each, an “SNS”), you allow Disruptor Beam to access certain information from your profile for that SNS. The information you allow Disruptor Beam to access varies by Service and SNS, and it is affected by the privacy settings you and your friends establish at the SNS. You can control and find out more about these settings at the SNS where you play our games. For example, Disruptor Beam may access and store some or all of the following information, as allowed by you, the SNS and your preferences:

• your first and last name  
• your profile picture or its URL  
• your user ID number, which is linked to publicly available information such as name and profile photo  
• the user ID numbers and other public data for your friends  
• the login e-mail you provided to that SNS when you registered  
• your gender  
• your birthday  
• other information the SNS provides to Disruptor Beam through its Application Programming Interface

When you interact with the Services (whether or not through an SNS), at any Disruptor Beam Site, We may collect and store information from you directly as described below.

Disruptor Beam may collect and share with other parties aggregate information and device-related information gathered by Disruptor Beam in the course of your use of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services. "Aggregate information" is information that describes the habits, usage patterns, and demographics of users as a group but does not describe or reveal the identity of any particular user. "Device-related information" is information about a user that is presented in a form distinguishable from information relating to other users, but not in a form that personally identifies contact and/or billing information for any user, or enables the recipient to communicate directly with any user unless agreed to by the user in advance of such communication (such as the device ID of your mobile device). Aggregate information and/or device-related information may be used by Disruptor Beam for any purpose, including, without limitation, to improve the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, for internal marketing studies, or simply to collect demographic information about Disruptor Beam's users.

Disruptor Beam may use contact information provided by users to send information about (i) Disruptor Beam and the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services for which you subscribed or otherwise used or accessed, including, without limitation, news about product updates, contests, events, and other promotional materials, and (ii) only if the users agree to receive such communications, for unrelated products or services. "Personal information" is information that permits a recipient to identify you as an individual, any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ('data subject'); an identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity, including but not limited to your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and credit card information. While Disruptor Beam collects personal information on a voluntary basis for the use of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, Disruptor Beam's collection of personal information may be a requirement for access to certain parts of the Disruptor Beam Sites or Services. We may collect personal information from you from a variety of ways, including, without limitation, when you (a) make an online purchase from the Disruptor Beam Sites, (b) register to become a member or user of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, (c) voluntarily provide it when you use the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, (d) disclose it in a public area of the Disruptor Beam Site and Services, or (e) provide it when you communicate with Us.

If you make an online purchase or register to become a member or user of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, We may use the personal information that you provide in connection with such purchase for shipping and billing purposes, to administer and manage your account, or provide promotional updates regarding such Disruptor Beam Sites and Services as contemplated above. In addition, We may send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical or security issues related to the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services you requested, confirming you requested a product or service, or providing periodic updates or information relating to the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services you requested. Except in the cases described below, Disruptor Beam will not share personal information with any third-party unless the user agrees to such disclosure in advance.

We may provide the option to register to receive SMS notifications to your mobile phone regarding the Services that you use. If you sign up to have SMS notifications sent directly to your mobile phone We will receive and store the information you provide, including your telephone number. These messages may notify you of in-game activity and may allow you to use the Service from your phone.

Mobile Applications

When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or “UDID”).

With your consent We may also send push notifications to your mobile device to provide game updates and other relevant messages. You can manage push notifications from the “options” or “settings” page within the relevant Service. You may also be able to manage them from your device’s settings page for the relevant Service. We may send local notifications to your mobile device to provide game updates and other relevant information. You can manage local notifications from the “options” or “settings” page within the relevant Service.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the application.

Information Sharing

Disruptor Beam may occasionally instruct other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including, without limitation, packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, answering customer questions about products or services, sending postal mail, providing billing and collection services, conducting customer surveys, and processing event registration. We will only provide these companies the information reasonably required to perform the applicable service, and they will be prohibited from using that information for any other purpose. When these companies collect and/or have access to the personal information you provide, We require that they protect the confidentiality of personal information they collect or have access to in the course of their engagement by Disruptor Beam. Also, in certain cases, your personal information may be collected directly by our authorized distributors, sublicensees or subcontractors in connection with certain products or services made available through web sites operated by such companies. In these cases, the privacy policies of such companies will apply rather than Disruptor Beam's policy. If providing the information is a requirement of usage, the user may elect to decline to use that particular product or service.

Disruptor Beam may elect to share personal information of users with certain business partners for marketing or other similar purposes, but only if the users agree to share such information. In such event, such partners will be prohibited from disclosing such information or using such information except for the limited purposes for which such users agree to share such information. Furthermore, third-party web sites and companies with links to and from the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services may collect personal information about users. You should be aware that these third-party web sites or links may have their own information collection practices and privacy policies. We do not control the privacy policies of third parties that have web sites linked to the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services. If you click on a third-party advertisement or link, the privacy policies of the third-party web site that you link to will govern the use of your information by that web site's operator. Disruptor Beam's Privacy Policy does not extend to these external web sites and companies. Please refer directly to these companies and web sites regarding their privacy policies. We assume no responsibility or liability for the actions of such third parties with respect to their use of your information or otherwise. Accordingly, please make sure you are aware of and comfortable with the privacy policies of any third-party web sites to which you follow a link.

Disruptor Beam may disclose your personal information or otherwise use such information to communicate with you if required or permitted to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process or any governmental request; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Disruptor Beam or its affiliated companies, licensors or licensees; (c) enforce the Terms of Service or any applicable License Agreements; or (d) protect the personal safety or interests of Disruptor Beam employees, users of Disruptor Beam products or services, or members of the public in urgent circumstances.

In the event of a merger or consolidation of Disruptor Beam, or the sale of all or a portion of its stock or assets, or the transfer of the operation and distribution of certain products or services to a third party, or bankruptcy of Disruptor Beam, your personal information may be transferred to Disruptor Beam's successors or assigns resulting from such events to use for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Children Under The Age of 13

Our Sites and Services are not intended for children under the age of 13 and We do not knowingly collect any personal information from such children. Children under the age of 13 should not use our Sites and Services at any time. In the event that We learn that We have inadvertently gathered personal information from children under the age of 13, We will take reasonable measures to erase such information from our records. We urge parents to instruct their children to never give out their real names, addresses, or phone numbers, without permission, when on-line. Teenagers between the ages of 13 and 17 must have their parents review this policy and they or their parents can contact Us if they would like to opt out of receiving communications from Us or to remove personal information.

Passive Collection

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

Cookies and Similar Technologies

Disruptor Beam and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service..

When you visit our Sites and/or Services we may send one or more cookies to your browser. They enable Us to store information about your device that is then used for matching certain other device related information that we collect via the browser. This helps us, amongst other things, to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Sites and/or Services and also allows us to improve our Sites and/or Services.

The table below explains what cookies are used on the Sites and Services.

Types of cookies / Who serves these cookies / How to refuse

 **Essential website cookies:**  These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our Site and to use some of its features, such as maintaining a login to our forums or your identity within a game.  Served by: disruptorbeam.com

Because these cookies are strictly necessary to deliver the Site to you, you cannot refuse them.

However, you can block or delete website cookies by changing your browser settings.

 **Performance and functionality cookies:**  These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our Site but are non-essential to their use. However, without these cookies, certain functionality may become unavailable.  Served by:  disruptorbeam.com

To refuse these cookies, please follow the instructions for your particular web browser or mobile device.

 **Analytics and customization cookies:**  These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help us understand how our Site is being used or to help us customize our Site for you.  We have elected to anonymize all of our data collected via Google Analytics.  Served by: disruptorbeam.com, google.com, appsflyer.com

To refuse these website cookies, please follow the instructions for your web-browser or mobile device.

Alternatively, please click on the relevant opt-out link below:

• Google Analytics: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

• AppsFlyer: contact privacy@appsflyer.com

 **Advertising cookies:**  These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests.  Served by: disruptorbeam.com, facebook.com

To refuse these cookies, please follow the instructions for your web browser or mobile device.

Alternatively, please click on the relevant opt-out link below:

• Facebook advertising: https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217

Blocking cookies

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies. You can exercise your cookie preferences by clicking on the appropriate opt-out links provided in the cookie table above.

You can also set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies, or modify the privacy settings on your mobile device. If you choose to reject cookies or modify the privacy settings on your device, you may still use our Sites and/or Services though your access to some functionality and areas of our Sites may be restricted. As the means by which you can refuse cookies through your web browser controls vary from browser-to-browser or for particular movile devices, you should visit your browser's help or mobile device documentation menu for more information.

Chat Rooms/Forums

From time to time, Disruptor Beam may provide online chat (voice or text) rooms and/or forums to users. Any information that is disclosed in these chat rooms and forums is public information and users should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in such chat rooms and forums. If you voluntarily disclose information in a public area of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, such as a voice or text chat room or forum, that information may be collected and used by a third party to send you unsolicited messages, advertisements or for other purposes. We do not control the actions of these third parties in public areas of the Disruptor Beam Sites and Services, so if you disclose information in a public area, you do so at your own risk.  We do not monitor or log any direct, private communication between users, unless it was requested by at least one participant in advance or if there is reason to believe that a user is using such direct communication in order to breach these ToS or any applicable law.

The Services support and may encourage interaction among players. In some Disruptor Beam Sites and Services your SNS friends may see your name, profile photo or descriptions of your game activity. In some Disruptor Beam Sites and Services other players may be able to see your Disruptor Beam account information, which may include your name or in certain cases may reveal your SNS ID. Access to a SNS ID may allow others to view the public information associated with your related SNS account, and other players may also be able to contact you through the related SNS’ communication channels.

Resumes

Disruptor Beam allows for the online submission of resumes via the Disruptor Beam corporate website. Please note that the information (including personal information) collected from a resume is not subject to this Privacy Policy. The information obtained from your resume will be used for the purpose of evaluating your application for a job with Disruptor Beam.

Choice/Opt-out

Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, Disruptor Beam provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from Disruptor Beam when you are asked to provide information and the option of discontinuing receipt of communications from Disruptor Beam by removing your information from Disruptor Beam's databases. Instructions for discontinuing receipt of communications from Disruptor Beam will be made available with the communication and on the related Disruptor Beam Site.

We partner with third parties to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising visit: http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/ or if located in the European Union visit: http://www.youronlinechoices.eu. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

Social Media Widgets

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

Storage and Transfer of Information

Personal information collected outside of the United States, including in the European Economic Area, is transferred to the United States. Your information is stored on our servers in the United States and potentially in other countries whose data protection laws may be different to the laws in your country. Please be assured that We take steps to protect your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Security of Information

We use appropriate technical, organizational and administrative measures to help protect any personal information We process about you. Such measures include the use of firewall technology to protect our servers, limitation of access to our databases to staff with a technical need to access such servers, requiring our developers to access our servers through encrypted virtual-private networks (VPNs) and storage of password information using one-way hashing algorithms.

Although We will use reasonable efforts to safeguard the privacy and security of your information, transmissions on the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure. Accordingly, We cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking or data loss will not occur, and We assume no responsibility or liability for disclosure of any of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access or other causes beyond our reasonable control. Accordingly, please use care when determining what information you elect to share with Us through the Disruptor Beam Sites or Services.

Your Role in Protecting Your Privacy

Please remember that protection of your privacy and the security of your information begins with you. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any account ID or password you use to register, and you should always be careful and responsible whenever disclosing information online. We caution you against giving out personal information to others online or in-game, as this information may be used for illegal or harmful purposes. We cannot control and shall not be responsible for how third parties may use the information that you elect to disclose publicly.

Corrections, Updates and Removal of Information

If you are concerned about the accuracy of personal information maintained by Disruptor Beam or would like your personal information removed from Disruptor Beam's records, you may use the tools, if any, made available with the particular Disruptor Beam Site or Service to update or remove such information, or you may contact Us by e-mail or mail at the address set forth below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. If you choose to delete your personal information, you may not be able to access some areas of the Disruptor Beam Sites or Services to which you have subscribed. For your protection, you may be required to provide proof of your identity to obtain a copy of your personal information. If you make a request to access your personal information, We may charge you a fee subject to a maximum specified by applicable law.

Upon request, Disruptor Beam will provide you with information about whether we hold, any of your personal information. To request this information please, contact us at **privacy@disruptorbeam.com**.

We will not provide a refund for any prepaid service which is inaccessible to you because of your deletion of personal information. We may still retain your information in our files, however, to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreements, and due to technical and legal requirements and constraints related to the security, integrity and operation of our web sites. To update or remove any information that is available to Disruptor Beam through a third-party service or SNS, you will need to follow that service’s instructions for updating your information.

Contacting Disruptor Beam

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by postal mail or email to:

Disruptor Beam, Inc.  
ATTN: Privacy Officer  
161 Worcester Rd., Suite 210  
Framingham, MA 01701

E-mail: privacy@disruptorbeam.com
